[Music]
hi everyone this is Ravi welcome to
prenti tasa Advanced Training as you all
know I've already published 52 YouTube
videos covering beginners intermediate
and advanced level Concepts so from
couple of videos onwards I've started
started teaching you some realtime
scenarios where you might encounter
different types of obstacles while
automating your test cases and I have
started explaining you how can we solve
those obstacles and this is our obstacle
11 in terms of realtime scenarios and
this is our lesson 53 in terms of
overall trient tasa Advanced Training so
in this lesson I'm going to teach you a
realtime scenario where you need to
add random
numbers by using math expressions and
then I'm also going to introduce you to
the user
simulation where we can use this user
simulation Concepts while solving the
obstacle please do subscribe to the
channel click on Bell icon you'll
receive notifications whenever I publish
more videos thank
you so this is our 11th obstacle named
as addition and it is categorized as
medium so let's go for it so let us see
what is the scenario that we need to
automate or what is the challenge that
we need to solve for input the sum of
two randomly generated numbers into the
sum field so basically
these are randomly generated numbers
random one number random two number and
you need to enter some of these two
random
numbers if I
enter the sum of these two numbers
correctly in the sum edit field then you
solve this automation problem if I do
let me try again this random numbers
keep changing okay so now
let us see how can we automate this
particular challenge let's go back to
our tricenter
sta as you all know we are capturing all
the objects related to each and every
obstacle that we covered in obstacles
module folder so let me right click on
this obstacles module
folder select scan and application
so select the application that you would
like to scan and click on scan
button and here you can see random one
random two and sum right so if you see
this is my random
one text and this is my random two
number
and then this is the
result okay so you can see here all
those controls are uniquely identified
this one is uniquely identified this is
uniquely identified this is uniquely
identified and here I would like to
rename this because these numbers are
not constant it's keep on changing so
I'm going to name this as number one
and this is my number two and if you see
the right side properties okay here I
can see I have ID and tag label I don't
want to select inner text because the
inner text keep changing but I can use
this inner text property to get the
value of this number right in the same
way for number two as well
and then result is your edit box okay so
now let us save this
module with obstacle name copy this
obstacle name and then paste it
here now save the
module and then close your xcam so let's
go back to our
prenta so this is our new module that we
added right number one number two result
so now let us create a test case so now
let's go back to our test case section
which is blue color right this is our
obstacles test case folder where we are
automating all the test cases related to
each and every obstacle right click on
this create a new test case name this as
the same obstacle name
name double click on this now to create
a test steps we need to drag this new
module that we created and drop onto
your test
case now let's expand
this what we need to do we need to First
capture the inner text of this object
and this object okay for that this is my
first number
one randomly generated number for this
select inner
text equal
to I'm going to store this into a num
one as a buffer value okay this is my
buffer name num one I'm instructing
tasar to
store the inner text of this object into
a buffer name num one and your action
mode should be
buffer right now again for object two
you need to store the inner text for
that click on this drop down select
inner text equal to buffer name I'm
going to give it as num two okay and
then your action mode should be
buffer now we need to add the Val values
that stored in these two
buffers and then print the result in
this edit box so how can we add the two
numbers by using the math function so
now let me show you how can we write the
math function any method or functions
that
we need to call in TSA we need to use
open curly
braces math see this is my math function
and open Square bra close Square braces
and close your curly bra this is my math
function notation right here I'm going
to
write the operator num one and num two
operators okay I mean here I'm going to
write actual formula what I'm going to
do here I need to call Buffer one and
then operator plus and then call Buffer
two
that's it okay for that to call Buffer
open curly braces capital B open Square
braces num one is my first
buffer close Square braces close curly
braces and then your operator plus now
you need to call your second buffer open
curly braces capital B open Square
braces num
to close Square braces close curly
braces so as soon as you click here it
should convert into this format if it is
not converted into the format means you
are making some mistake let's say if I
remove this curly braces see now it is
not converted into the for format that
means this is wrong just right click and
then translate value see it throws an
error M message see unexpected end value
token if I correct
this now now it converted to this format
right click and then translate value so
then see your expression found correctly
click okay so
now here the action mode should be input
so now before I mark this test case as
completed let's run this test case and
see if it works right
click so before that let me save this
right click and run in
scratchbook see here now it added 68 and
48 and then it entered the result 116
But If You observe closely we did not
get the popup saying
that you are automation problem solved
successfully why because we have just
inputed this particular value we haven't
typed it if you type this right then
only you'll get it but what we did we
just input the value so that doesn't
trigger the US user simulation basically
you need to make sure that when you
enter the value you need to pass the
user simulation how can we do that there
are two methods one is you can send the
keys so that that it simulates the
keyboard how can I do that to send the
keys again open curly braces send
Keys open Square
braces and here close Square braces C
close close curly braces so here now
send case what I'm sending this buffer
Plus second buffer I'm sending right now
save this and let me run this now I
should get the success
message see now it entered the
correct result and you got this you
solve this automation problem why simple
if you are using a keyword called send
Keys it's simp Ates the your system
keyboard that's why you are getting the
success message there is another method
to perform user simulation how let me
delete this send case here
now okay the next method is let's go
back to your modules okay
here I can perform user simulation by
introducing steering pyram meter how
let's go here now we are entering the
value here right while entering I need
to perform user simulation so go to this
object in the module this is my object
result is the object so for this object
you need to add an additional steering
parameter how right click here on the
module select create steering
parameter here the parameter name should
be user no space capital S
simulation so you need to make sure that
spelling is correct user no space
Capital
yes simulation okay now this user
simulation should be
true basically what what I'm instructing
tasa consider this edit box as a user
simulation box so whatever you input
here
that should take your user simulation
consider this as user is entering it
okay so now let's save this now okay let
me now let's save this test case and let
me run this one before running this I
would like to mark this test case as
completed work state completed
completed save this now let's run this
again okay this time also I'm not using
send Keys here right but still I should
get automation solved successfully
message so it
should add two random
values see here now it entered
successfully and I got this you solve
this automation problem also right so
that is how
you can
perform random number
additions how we can use send keys and
how we can use user
simulations so if you have any queries
leave your queries in the comment box
I'll try to respond to your queries
thank you
[Music]